# GUILLERMO MARTIN

Alameda, CA 94501

Phone: (757) 620-2701 | Email: <a href="mailto:gscalica@gmail.com">gscalica@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guillermo-martin-10441046/ | Github: https://github.com/Guillermo-Martin

| Portfolio: https://guillermo-martin.github.io/qcm-portfolio/

## SUMMARY

Junior Web Developer with two years of experience creating and updating Web pages from high-fidelity designs for Sift's Marketing site. Eager to learn and apply UX design skills in order to improve or create pleasant user experiences and improve my skills as a Web developer.

## SKILLS

**Web Development:** HTML5, Pug, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Git, responsive Web development **UX Design (in progress):** Wireframing, usability studies, low- and high-fidelity prototyping, Figma, responsive Web design, user stories and journeys, affinity diagramming, user research

### EXPERIENCE

## **Junior Web Developer**

Sift - https://sift.com/, San Francisco, CA

August 2021 – Present

- Major accomplishments:
  - Collaborated with graphic designers and the Content Marketing team to create the <u>Fraud Intelligence Center</u> page (which I update quarterly) and <u>Fraud Schemes</u> page.
  - Created Sift's <u>Brand Guidelines</u> page with minimal guidance.
- Collaborated with graphic designers and the Content Marketing team in order to determine the feasibility of requirements and to ensure accuracy of the final product.
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of numerous Web pages, including Sift's Trust and Safety University, Product, Partners, and Legal pages.
- Updated Sift's Marketing site to adhere to the new brand design following a brand refresh.
- Changed Sift's Legal pages to the brand's new design to increase the readability of text heavy pages with minimal guidance.
- Ensured responsive Website behavior without the aid of tablet and mobile mockups.
- Created developer documentation for Sift's Marketing site and Wordpress sites (Resources and Blog) to ease new developer onboarding.
- Assisted graphic designers with resizing customer logos to a more standardized size for use in company assets using Adobe Illustrator.
- Created a Marketo template to streamline Marketing campaign efforts for the Marketing Operations team.

## Freelance Web Developer

June 2020 – September 2020

Oakland Peace Center - https://www.oaklandpeacecenter.org/, Oakland, CA

- Redesigned the Website using Squarespace, HTML5, and CSS3 in order to streamline user experience (UX) and create a more appealing and engaging user interface (UI).
- Collaborated with Board Members in order to maintain the company brand and improve brand awareness.
- Provided training on the use of Squarespace to the Donor Engagement Manager.

## ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Criminalist III (Forensic Scientist)

Alameda County Sheriff's Office, Oakland, CA

May 2009 – July 2019

 Responsibilities: conducting independent laboratory examination and analysis on hundreds of cases in Forensic Biology and DNA, documenting findings in laboratory reports, processing crime scenes and conducting vehicle examinations, conducting technical and administrative reviews, testifying as an expert witness, and managing the exchange of criminally-sensitive information with local, state, and national law enforcement agencies.

#### EDUCATION

Google UX Design Professional Certificate (in progress): Coursera, self-study.

Completed five out of the seven required courses. The certificate covers the following: Foundations of User Experience design, the UX design process, wireframing, creating low-fidelity prototypes, conducting UX research and testing, creating high-fidelity designs and prototypes in Figma, and responsive Web design.

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of California, Berkeley Extension, Berkeley, CA A rigorous and fast-paced, 12-week full-time, Full Stack Web Development course that covers the theory and application of Web development to provide the knowledge and skills to build full stack Web applications and to become a full stack Web developer. The following topics were covered in this program: Browser Based Technologies, API Interaction, Server Side Development, Databases, Quality Assurance, Deployment/Command-Line Fundamentals, and Computer Science applied to JavaScript.

Master of Science, Forensic Science: University of Central Oklahoma, Edmond, OK

Non-degree coursework in Cellular and Molecular Biology: Old Dominion University, Norfolk, VA

Bachelor of Science, Biology: James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA